<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miguel Moravec&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Miguel Moravec&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://miguelmoravec.com/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GSC Platform</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/gsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/gsc/</guid>
      <description>Hey all! I&amp;rsquo;m running to serve as your GSC President for the 2022 academic year. This page is organized as follows:
 Platform Summary About Me Priority Agenda Topics  1) Platform Summary Listen First 👂  Invitation to exec meetings and convos with admins Report-outs from 2-3 depts per month Open office hours  Leverage Platform 💪  Collect data from surveys and referandums Pass and distribute data-driven resolutions Broadcast graduate student needs to community and admin  Build Coalitions that Win 📣  Partner with Energetic Grad student orgs Restart relationship with Hustler Student Newspaper Invest in Faculty and Undergraduate Senate Needs  2) About Me I recently spoke with Zach Joseph from the Vanderbilt Hustler about who I am and what I wanted to do in GSC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Written in Go, Hugo is an open source static site generator available under the Apache Licence 2.0. Hugo supports TOML, YAML and JSON data file types, Markdown and HTML content files and uses shortcodes to add rich content. Other notable features are taxonomies, multilingual mode, image processing, custom output formats, HTML/CSS/JS minification and support for Sass SCSS workflows.
Hugo makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Activism</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/doresdivest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/doresdivest/</guid>
      <description>Miguel is the co-founder of Dores Divest, a student activist campaign that made international headlines in February 2022 for filing a novel legal complaints regarding Vanderbilt&amp;rsquo;s fossil fuel investments. Learn more here.
Articles with quotes from Miguel:  Washington Post: Legal Complaint Exclusive Vanderbilt Hustler: Al Gore Endorsement Stanford Daily: Activism Commentary  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Mentor</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/stemseas2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/stemseas2/</guid>
      <description>As a Vanderbilt undergraduate, Miguel Moravec took part in a research cruise that used multibeam sonar to map areas of the Queen Charlotte Fault off the Southeast Alaskan coast. He and other students also visited Exit Glacier Park and saw first-hand how fast glacier ice had receded over the past 50 years.
“It was really impactful,” said Moravec, now a Ph.D. student in civil and environmental engineering. “I really wanted to get involved in climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Scholar</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/princeton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/princeton/</guid>
      <description>In 2016, Miguel worked with NOAA scientists to analyze climate data, automatically generate relevant figures/plots, and ultimately contribute science to the North-American Multi-Model Ensemble, as hosted by Princeton University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences.
Check out this newsletter from Princeton University featuring my work here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Research</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/pipeline/</guid>
      <description>A recent study has concluded that cities in middle and eastern Tennessee with access to barged petroleum products suffered less during the May shutdown of the Colonial Pipeline.
Vanderbilt University conducted the research in as part of a case study on resilience strategies for navigable portions and associated infrastructure of the Cumberland/Tennessee river couplet system.
Janey Camp and Craig Philip, both research associate professors of civil and environmental engineering and associate director and director of the Vanderbilt Center for Transportational and Operational Resiliency, respectively, are leading the ongoing research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
