<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on Miguel Moravec&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on Miguel Moravec&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://miguelmoravec.com/en/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to break into Climate Policy</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/how_to_climate_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/how_to_climate_policy/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow Earth warrior! If you’re reading this blog, you may be asking yourself what you need to “make it” into a rewarding career of climate policy.
Whether you’re early in your undergraduate career or looking to make a switch from some other industry, today I’m going to walk you through my journey from DC-reject to a full-blown policy professional who’s briefed policymakers from the Hill to New Mexico.
It took me 4 years and as many major setbacks to finally make it to the climate “room where it happens,” but boy was it worth the wait!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSC Platform</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/gsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/gsc/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Thanks for electing me to be your GSC President! Read on to see some of the issues we&amp;rsquo;ll be taking on together next year.
This page is organized as follows:
 Platform Summary About Me Priority Agenda Topics  1) Platform Summary Listen First 👂  Invitation to exec meetings and convos with admins Report-outs from 2-3 depts per month Open office hours  Leverage Platform 💪  Collect data from surveys and referandums Pass and distribute data-driven resolutions Broadcast graduate student needs to community and admin  Build Coalitions that Win 📣  Partner with Energetic Grad student orgs Restart relationship with Hustler Student Newspaper Invest in Faculty and Undergraduate Senate Needs  2) About Me I recently spoke with Zach Joseph from the Vanderbilt Hustler about who I am and what I wanted to do in GSC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Activism</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/doresdivest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/doresdivest/</guid>
      <description>Miguel is the co-founder of Dores Divest, a student activist campaign that made international headlines in February 2022 for filing a novel legal complaints regarding Vanderbilt&amp;rsquo;s fossil fuel investments. Learn more here.
Articles covering our actions:  Washington Post: Legal Complaint Exclusive CNN: Legal Complaint Coverage Vanderbilt Hustler: Al Gore Endorsement Stanford Daily: Activism Commentary  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Mentor</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/stemseas2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/stemseas2/</guid>
      <description>As a Vanderbilt undergraduate, Miguel Moravec took part in a research cruise that used multibeam sonar to map areas of the Queen Charlotte Fault off the Southeast Alaskan coast. He and other students also visited Exit Glacier Park and saw first-hand how fast glacier ice had receded over the past 50 years.
“It was really impactful,” said Moravec, now a Ph.D. student in civil and environmental engineering. “I really wanted to get involved in climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
