<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on Miguel Moravec&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on Miguel Moravec&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://miguelmoravec.com/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lawmakers from 15 states learn multimodal strategy</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/ncel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/ncel/</guid>
      <description>Miguel presented during the 2025 National Caucus of Environmental Legislators (NCEL) Annual Forum sharing state-level strategies that expand clean transportation choices and reduce household costs.
During the presentation, Miguel highlighted how states such as Colorado, Virginia, and Minnesota are advancing legislation that increases access to transit, walking, biking, and other clean mobility options—policies that also support local economic development, raise property values, and cut climate pollution.
The session drew an audience of approximately 60 elected officials and featured contributions from fellow panelists:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel presents at TRB with USDOT</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/trb_usdot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/trb_usdot/</guid>
      <description>During the 2025 Transportation Research Board conference, Miguel collaborated with USDOT staff during several events to represent how federal tools and research were impacting on the ground policy outcomes. These collaborations included:
 &amp;ldquo;Progress in Accounting for Induced Vehicle Travel&amp;rdquo; USDOT Lectern Session Panelist &amp;ldquo;Crafting a National Climate Change Research Agenda&amp;rdquo; USDOT Closed Door Meeting  Notably, Miguel was invited by USDOT to serve as a panelist during a lectern session titled &amp;ldquo;Progress in Accounting for Induced Vehicle Travel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Impact Review</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/media24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/media24/</guid>
      <description>Miguel is a national thought leader on transportation topics including VMT reduction strategies, state fiscal policy, federal funding solutions, and clean transport co-benefits.
Miguel and analysis from his Smarter MODES Calculator were referenced 28 times in earned media in 2024.
Quotes  1/22 Heatmap - Transit Agencies Are Climate Agencies, Too 1/22 Yahoo Finance - Transit Agencies Are Climate Agencies, Too 2/8 Greater Greater Washington - A law to get climate and transportation on the same page in Maryland 2/12 The Baltimore Banner - Maryland transportation officials have ambitious climate goals - can they get there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Induced Demand Dashboard Demo</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/demo_claude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/demo_claude/</guid>
      <description>Concept tool for predicting induced demand emissions in greater detail than the RMI SHIFT calculator Note: Sample data used - not yet for real world applications.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts: Miguel Talks Clean Transport</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Active Towns - E274 Talking Induced Demand and much more Host John Simmerman and I discuss the opportunities to curb the negative climate impacts of our current car-dependent approach to transportation by providing more sustainable mobility mode choices, such as walking, biking, and transit.
City Climate Corner - E53 Transportation Emissions and VMT Host Rep. Larry Kraft (Minnesota) and Abby Finis (local Climate Solutions) talk clean transportation with me and Anna Zetkulic, RMI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel briefs the Hill</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/hill/</guid>
      <description>In a briefing on Capitol Hill, T4A Policy Associate Corrigan Salerno showed how highway expansion funds in the IIJA dwarfed historic investments in public transit leading to disastrous GHG emissions increases. The short and sweet of it is that mode-shift needs to be coupled with electrification to decrease our GHG emissions. Taylor Reich from the Institute for Transportation &amp;amp; Development Policy explained that coupling electrifying transportation with mode shift (opportunities to travel outside of a car) will save the government and private citizens trillions, lower energy consumption, and lower emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to break into Climate Policy</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/how_to_climate_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/how_to_climate_policy/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow Earth warrior! If you’re reading this blog, you may be asking yourself what you need to “make it” into a rewarding career of climate policy.
Whether you’re early in your undergraduate career or looking to make a switch from some other industry, today I’m going to walk you through my journey from DC-reject to a full-blown policy professional who’s briefed policymakers from the Hill to New Mexico.
It took me 4 years and as many major setbacks to finally make it to the climate “room where it happens,” but boy was it worth the wait!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRA Energy Community Mapping</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/pnw_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/pnw_map/</guid>
      <description>I created the following interactive map in R using the Leaflet App. It dynamically depicts which census tract neighborhoods in Washington and Oregon are Energy Communities, Tribal Lands, or considered disadvantaged by White House CJEST or DOE DAC metrics.
Note the purple areas, which indicates neighborhoods that are both energy communities and considered disadvantaged by the federal government. These areas may be advantageous for clean energy investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSC Platform</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/gsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/gsc/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Thanks for electing me to be your GSC President! Read on to see some of the issues we&amp;rsquo;ll be taking on together next year.
This page is organized as follows:
 Platform Summary About Me Priority Agenda Topics  1) Platform Summary Listen First 👂  Invitation to exec meetings and convos with admins Report-outs from 2-3 depts per month Open office hours  Leverage Platform 💪  Collect data from surveys and referandums Pass and distribute data-driven resolutions Broadcast graduate student needs to community and admin  Build Coalitions that Win 📣  Partner with Energetic Grad student orgs Restart relationship with Hustler Student Newspaper Invest in Faculty and Undergraduate Senate Needs  2) About Me I recently spoke with Zach Joseph from the Vanderbilt Hustler about who I am and what I wanted to do in GSC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Activism</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/doresdivest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/doresdivest/</guid>
      <description>Miguel is the co-founder of Dores Divest, a student activist campaign that made international headlines in February 2022 for filing a novel legal complaints regarding Vanderbilt&amp;rsquo;s fossil fuel investments. Learn more here.
Articles covering our actions:  Washington Post: Legal Complaint Exclusive CNN: Legal Complaint Coverage Vanderbilt Hustler: Al Gore Endorsement Stanford Daily: Activism Commentary  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Mentor</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/stemseas2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/blog/stemseas2/</guid>
      <description>As a Vanderbilt undergraduate, Miguel Moravec took part in a research cruise that used multibeam sonar to map areas of the Queen Charlotte Fault off the Southeast Alaskan coast. He and other students also visited Exit Glacier Park and saw first-hand how fast glacier ice had receded over the past 50 years.
“It was really impactful,” said Moravec, now a Ph.D. student in civil and environmental engineering. “I really wanted to get involved in climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
