<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Miguel Moravec&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Miguel Moravec&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://miguelmoravec.com/en/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data Map: Multimodal Assets</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/port_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/port_map/</guid>
      <description>As part of a forthcoming Department of Homeland Security Resilience Guide, I created an interactive map of key multimodal infrastructure assets for major economic centers along the Tennessee and Cumberland Rivers.
Chattanooga Critical Transportation Infrastructure Click the arrows &amp;raquo; to access the legend  .embed-container {position: relative; padding-bottom: 80%; height: 0; max-width: 100%;} .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container iframe{position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;} small{position: absolute; z-index: 40; bottom: 0; margin-bottom: -15px;} The map above indicates the location of Chattanooga water way infrastructure, such as public ports and locks, in relation to Class I rail and Primary Roadways (highways).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Dashboard: Debris Forecast</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/nashzero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/nashzero/</guid>
      <description>The following interactive dashboard was created for our client, the Metropolitan Government of Nashville, as part of a team Data Science Institute effort. The dashboard forecasts debris permit and tonnage generation under a range of scenarios.

Click &amp;raquo; here &amp;laquo; to launch dashboard Background Metro Nashville has set a goal to be solid landfill neutral by 2050. As a rapidly growing city, one of the major sources of solid waste is through development (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NOAA Climate Modeling Work</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/princeton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/princeton/</guid>
      <description>In 2016, Miguel worked with NOAA scientists to analyze climate data, automatically generate relevant figures/plots, and ultimately contribute science to the North-American Multi-Model Ensemble, as hosted by Princeton University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences.
Check out this newsletter from Princeton University featuring my work here.
Automatic Post-Processing Output Examples Sea Surface Temperature Anomaly Sea Surface Temperature RMSE Reference Temperature Anomaly </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Resilience Research</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/pipeline/</guid>
      <description>I completed analysis for a study that concluded that cities in middle and eastern Tennessee with access to barged petroleum products suffered less during the May shutdown of the Colonial Pipeline.
I found a novel relationship between federal waterborne petroleum volumes and crowd sourced Gas buddy station outage data that helped explain how the disruption affected certain southeastern markets.
My research team and I conducted the research in as part of a case study on resilience strategies for navigable portions and associated infrastructure of the Cumberland/Tennessee river couplet system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/pipeline-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/pipeline-copy/</guid>
      <description>A recent study has concluded that cities in middle and eastern Tennessee with access to barged petroleum products suffered less during the May shutdown of the Colonial Pipeline.
Vanderbilt University conducted the research in as part of a case study on resilience strategies for navigable portions and associated infrastructure of the Cumberland/Tennessee river couplet system.
Janey Camp and Craig Philip, both research associate professors of civil and environmental engineering and associate director and director of the Vanderbilt Center for Transportational and Operational Resiliency, respectively, are leading the ongoing research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data Map: Real Estate</title>
      <link>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelmoravec.com/en/blog/thesis/</guid>
      <description>The following interactive map was created in R using the Shiny App. It dynamically depicts the increases in the mean, median, and normalized sales price per census tract neighborhood.
 Increase in Median Sales Price in Davidson County, 2013-2016 (%) This map was created as part of my senior honor&amp;rsquo;s thesis at Vanderbilt University. For the project, I extracted over 60,000 real estate transactions from the Nashville Property Assesor&amp;rsquo;s office API using python scripts to make a comprehensive record of all sales in Davidson County between 2013 and 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
